this is another Katrina a puzzle and
it's my goal to solve all of these hey
guys this looks like a fun one we got a
polygon with multiple angles given and
it wants us to find the missing angle
and we're also given that this length is
equal to this length and it's this part
that makes it a little bit trickier if
you want to try it on your own pause it
right now cuz I'm going to solve it in 3
2 1 so first let's just go around and
Mark all the angles that we can we have
the 70° this angle right here is also
70° these are called vertical angles and
vertical angles are congruent next we
can focus right here and these are
called a linear pair these two angles
will always add up to 180° so this one's
going to be
110° and then once again because of
vertical angles this one is also 110°
next let's focus on this triangle here
the sum of the interior angles of any
triangle is 180° so 110 + 50 is equal to
160 that leaves 20° for this angle and
then we can move over to this triangle
we have 70° in 80° is equal to 150° that
leaves 30° for this angle and then next
let's go to this linear pair if this
angle is 80° that leaves 100° for this
angle and then we can look at this
quadrilateral in any quadrilateral the
sum of the interior angles is equal to
360° 110 + 100 + 60 is equal to 270 that
leaves us 90° for this last angle and
now we've pretty much found every single
angle except for the question mark and
this angle up here let's let's call this
other angle X unfortunately we can't
focus on this triangle because we have
two unknown angles in this triangle but
we still haven't taken advantage of the
fact that these two things are equal so
let's focus on the triangle that
contains these two equal lengths every
single triangle can be inscribed inside
of a circle it doesn't matter if it's
right obtuse or acute they can all fit
inside a circle and another fun fact for
any inscribed right angle triangle the
hypotenuse will be a diameter of the
circle and this is tied to the fact that
an inscribed angle is 1/ of the arc that
it subtends so for example an inscribed
angle of 30° will have a 60° Arc and an
inscribed angle of 45° would have a 90°
Arc and an inscribed angle of 90° would
have an arc of 180° and that'd be half
the circle and that's what makes this
the diameter and then since these two
portions are congruent that means this
is the center of the circle so each of
these are radi of the circle and now
let's bring all this stuff back and it
looks like this is on the circle but we
don't know that for sure let's see if we
can prove it we can focus on this
triangle right here and then this 20 and
30° is going to make this angle 50°
since both of these angles are equal to
50° that means this is an isoceles
triangle and in every Isles triangle the
sides opposite the congruent angles are
also congruent so this side is equal to
this side and since we know this side is
a radius that means this side would also
be a radius so that means this point up
here does lie on the circle so now we
have an inscribed quadrilateral we do
know one specific property about any
inscribed quadrilateral the opposite
angles add up to 180° so in these notes
a plus c equal 180 and B + D equal 180
and for our quadrilateral 50 + 90 +
question mark would equal 180 and 60 +
50 + x = 180 but we don't need this
second one because this equation will be
enough to solve for a question mark So
50 + 90 is equal to 140 and then to get
the question mark alone we can subtract
140 from both sides un left hand side
these will cancel each other out leaving
us with question mark and on the right
hand side 180 minus 140 is equal to 40
so our question mark is equal to 40
let's give it a label of degrees and
this is the answer to our question let's
put a box around it how exciting